Guide to the Hoover Institution Archives Photograph Card Catalog
Hoover Institution Archives
- Mitchell (Anna V.S.) Collection, 593 prints / 60 negatives / 9 envelopes (Box 67016 - 8.24)
  - 43 prints dealing with A. Mitchell's relief work with Russian refugees in Istanbul, undated (Folder A)
  - 23 prints / album dealing with Russian Cossaks in Bulgaria and Serbia, undated (Box B)
  - 1 print of Anna V. S. Mitchell in Washington, D. C, early 1900's (Folder C)
  - 28 prints depicting scenes of WW I devastation in France, undated (Folder D)
  - 421 prints depicting scenes of WW I devastation and relief work by Anna V. S. Mitchell in France, 1919-1921 (Folder E-H)
  - 60 negatives from the above prints, undated (Box I)
- Moffett (Guy) Collection, 1957; 1 slide / 2 negatives / 2 photos plus 5 dups. / 1 envelope (Box 57008 - 10.A-V)
  Scenes of Herbert Hoover's house in Kalgoorlie, Australia; slide is in color.
- Moley (Raymond) Collection, undated; 94 photos / 5 envelopes (Box 68008 - 10 A-V)
  - 18 photos of Franklin D. Roosevelt at the 1932 Democratic Convention, during the 1932 Presidential Campaign, with Raymond Moley, and in Portrait pose (autographed) (Folder A)
    Includes photo of scenes from the Convention and the Campaign.
  - 7 photos of colleagues and acquaintances of Raymond Moley, including Alf Landon (autographed) Gus Hall (autographed), Robert LaFollette (autographed), Earl Warren (autographed), Eamon de Valera (autographed), and Herbert Hoover with a group, 1950 (Box B)
  - 15 photos of Raymond Moley and of colleagues, including James Farley and Thomas Dewey, and of F.D. Roosevelt during the 1932 campaign, including Florida assassination attempt, and with State Dept. officials and foreign delegations, and of F.D. Roosevelt in 1933, signed by Raymond Moley, Elliott Roosevelt, James Farley, Sam Rosenman and others (Folder C)
  - 33 miscellaneous photos, 1950s (Box D)
    Includes photos of Goodwin Knight.
  - 20 miscellaneous photos, undated (Box E)
    Includes photo of William Jenning Bryan and of Barry Goldwater.
- Mollenhauer, Tekla (Van Norman) Collection, circa 1919-1920; 1 print / 1 envelope (Box 78065 - 10.A-V)
  Depicts Jozef Posudski and Ignacy Paderewski in Warsaw.
- Monday (Mark) collection, undated; 54 photos / 2 envelopes (Box 74063 - 10.A-V)
  - 37 photos of Minutemen network 989, concerning the Denver training camp, undated (Folder A)
  - 17 photos of arms, explosives and other military equipment used by the Minuteman, undated (Box B)
- Montrose, (Sherman) Collection, undated; 47 photos / 2 envelopes (Box XX248 - 8.09)
  - 10 photos from the Pacific and European theatres during W.W. II, including photos of Sherman Montrose, undated (Folder mA dr.4)
  - 37 photos from the Soloman Islands, France, and Italy during W.W. II, undated (Folder mB)
- Moore (Willam C.) Collection, 1 photo album; 1 scrapbook, 1 pamphlet / 1 small box (Box 77060 - 8M.02 Album f)
  Scrapbook concerning the beginning of WWI, 1914; Also photo album depicting the First Boy Scout in International Jamboree in London, England, 1920; and pamphlet, entitled "How to be a Soldier, containing cartoons, etc. about military life, 1917.
- Moravskii (V.I.) Collection, undated; 62 prints / 2 envelopes (Box 48009 - 8M.30 - 10.A.V.)
  - 51 miscellaneous prints, undated (Folder A)
    Includes 12 postcard caricatures of members of the Maritime Parliamen; * Yenisei Okhrana file photos of Bolshevik revolutionaries, including F. Dzerzhinski, L. Kamanev, L. Krasin, V.I. Lenin, M. Litvinov, J. Stalin, L. Trotsky and G. Zinoviev; 2 prints of visit by Chiang Kai-shek to Soviet Consulate in Shanghai.
  - 11 prints of Japanese groups and individuals, undated (Box B)
    Includes portraits of Gen. Taga and Count Okuma.
  - 10 glass plates of documents found in the collection, undated (Folder 14 (8M.30))
- Moreland, Jr. (William D.) Collection, 533 prints / 270 negatives / 8 envelopes (Box 59002 - 10.A-V)
  - 38 prints of Dahomey, Gold Coast, Nigeria, 1949 (Folder A)
  - 49 prints of French Guinea, 1949 (Box B)
  - 64 prints of Ivory Coast, Togo, Niger, 1949 (Folder C)
  - 96 prints of Sudan, 1949-1950 (Folder D-E)
  - 48 prints of Upper Volta, Senegal, Mauritania, 1949-1950 (Box F)
  - 238 prints, smaller copies of the large ones, undated (Box G)
  - 270 negatives, undated (Box H)
- Moscow. Conference Collection, October, 1943; 11 prints / 1 envelope (Box XX537 - 10.A-V)
  Eleven photographs of American, British and Soviet delegates to the Tripartite Conference in Moscow.
- Muhr (Allan H.) Collection, 1917; 43 prints / 13 negatives / 1 envelope (Box 74012 - 10.A-V)
  43 prints and 13 negatives depicting the U.S. Army, Lafayette Flying Corps in France. Included is a ceremony of July 4, 1917, when the first American Flag receive Croix de Guerre.
- Munson (Frederick P.) Collection, 1942-1943; 31 prints / 1 envelope (Box 74050 - 10.A-V Envelope A)
  31 captured prints, containing various group scenes of Imperial Japanese Army and Government personnel, photos of individuals and family members.
- Murphy, Robert D. Collection, 1298 prints / 50 postcards / 2 postcard folders / 1 drawing (copy) / 9 negatives / 1 album (Box 78060 - 10.A-V)
- Mussolini, Benito Collection, undated; 7 prints / 1 envelope (Box 58006 - 10.)
  7 prints.
- Myers, Robert John Collection, undated; 10 negatives / 1 envelope (Box 95069 - 10.A-V Envelope A)
  Depicts Korean troops during World War II.
- Nason, John W. Collection, 29 prints / 1 envelope (Box 83003 - 10.A-V)
  9 prints of John Nason, circa 1921-1962; 1 print of Mr. and Mrs. Nason, 1962; 5 prints of a dinner of the Nisei Student Relocation Commemorative Fund, Inc., 1982; 4 prints of a university centennial celebration, 1951; 5 prints of the 60th anniversary dinner of the Foreign Policy Association, 1977; and 5 prints of various meetings or groups, 1967-1987
- National Committee on Food for the Small Democracies Collection, 74 prints and postcards / 6 envelopes (Box XX404 - Photo File)
  - 5 prints depicting Howard E. Kershner, undated (Folder A)
  - 6 prints depicting prominent women, including Dorothy Dunbar Bromley, Geraldine Farrar, Margaret E. Sangster and Faith Baldwin, undated (Box B)
  - 6 prints depicting Herbert Hoover's trip to Finland, 1938 (Folder C)
  - 1 print depicting bound volumes of resolutions, undated (Box D)
  - 46 prints depicting scenes in Norway after the German invasion, undated (Box E)
  - 10 postcards depicting scenes of Belgium, 1940-1941 (Box F)
- Needham, Guy E. Collection, 1917-1919; 108 prints / 2 envelopes (Box 73038 - 10.A-V Envelope A-B)
  108 photographs pertaining to G. Needham's service in the U.S. Army, A.E.F, during World War I in France.
- Nelson (Mrs. Albert M.) Collection, undated; 40 photographs / 2 envelopes (Box 72006 - 10.A-V)
  - 19 photographs depicting U.S. Fleet activities at Yokosuka, Japan: construction of a pier "(Sherman Pier") and of caissons, 1954 (Folder A)
  - 21 photos taken on the occasion of the signing of the truce by UN Supreme Commander Mark W. Clark at his headquarters near Munsan, Korea, undated (Box B)
    1953
- New Left Collection, 1969-1974; 6 prints and contact sheets and negative strips / 1 envelope (Box 69001 - Photo file Envelope A)
  6 prints and contact sheets, 3 slides, and negatives and negative strips, depicting student radicalism and unrest at Stanford University.
- Newsom (John F.) Collection, 21 envelopes / 1 negative / ? prints (Box 6602 - 10.A-V; Rr.)
  - 20 prints, including photos of Herbert Hoover, J.F. Newsom, John C. Branner, George M. Richardson, Joseph Swain, and John H. Means, 1895-1917 (Folder A)
  - 4 photos of an Arkansas mountaineers home, undated (Box B)
  - 26 photos, 1 neg., of Stanford University in 1906, before the big earthquake, undated (Folder C)
  - 17 envelopes with photos of mine (shafts and drifts, hydraulic elevators, power plants, etc.), tin mining operations (wheeling and trucking, ground sluicing, gravel pumping, dredging, puddling etc.) in Mayala (Malay peninsula). Also some general photos of Malaya, 1920 (Folder D-T)
  - 1 envelope with miscellaneous photos of Malaya, and daily life in Malaya, undated (Folder Um)
  - 7 albums with photos depicting daily life and tin mining operations in Malaya. (1 album missing, 12/12/1974), 1920 (Folder f)
- Nicolaevsky, Boris I. Collection, undated; 533 prints, 172 negatives, 2 albums, 1 bas-relief, 1 daguerreotype / 17 envelopes, 1 album box, 1 oversize envelope. (Box 63013 - 10A-V)
  See register, Series No. 297, for list of photographs.
- Nicolas, Prince of Romania Collection, undated; 319 prints / 10 envelopes, 2 albums (Boxes 8-9) (Box 82002 - 11.63)
- Norway - History - 1945 - Collection, 3 prints / 1 envelope (Box SX204 - 10.A-V)
  Photos of Prince Olaf of Norway's homecoming, May 13, 1945; the King of Norway's homecoming, June 7, 1945; and the surrender of the Norwegian fortress "Alkershus," May 11, 1945
- Nowak, Bohdan, 1900- Collection, circa 1930s; 1 portfolio of 12 drawings / 1 envelope (Box mXX540 - 10.A-V)
  Portfolio of reproductions of drawings (printed with accompanying text in French), entitled "Vox Mortuum" (Voice of the Dead), by Bohdan Nowak, a Polish artist, depicting the horrors of war.
- Noxon, Samuel H. Collection, circa 1908-1929 (Box 90110 - 8M.02 Album fA)
  1 album of photographs depicting American residents and scenes in Shanghai and other locations in China and the Far East.
- Oberlin, B. G. Collection, 16 prints / 2 envelopes (Box 79043 - Photo file)
  - 1 print depicting Iva Toguri d'Aquino ("Tokyo Rose") leaving Sugamo prison in Japan, October 25, 1946 (Folder A)
  - 16 prints depicting B. G. Oberlin and his wife Doris in Japan following World War II; Sugamo Prison in Tokyo; and views of Japan, 1946-1948 (Box B)
- O'Brien, Charles A. Collection, 1918-1920; 234 prints, 3 drawings, and miscellaneous printed matter / 1 album (Box 78070 - 8M.02)
  234 prints and 3 drawings of Red Cross activity in Siberia, including prints of the railroads, bridges, troops and combat in the area from Vladivostok to Irkutsk during the Russian Civil War and the intervention of the American Expeditionary Forces.
- Olga, Consort of George I, King of the Hellenes Collection, 666 prints / 2 albums (Box 85049 - 8M.02)
  See inventory for description of albums
- Orbison, Thomas J. Collection, undated; 5 slides / 1 slide box (Box XX107 - Slide cabinet Slide box 1)
  5 slides depicting the covers of the albums in the collection.
- Orion, Walter Harold Collection, 1894-, 1948; 31 prints and post cards / 1 envelope (Box 79003 - 10.A-V)
  Depicts buildings and scenes of daily life in Seoul and rural areas of South Korea.
- Orlowski, A. Collection, 1819 (Box mSX191 - 10.A-V)
  Printed reproduction of a drawing by A. Orlowski, depicting two riders in a Central Asian setting.
- Osusky, Stepan Collection, 182 prints / Boxes 126-128 (Box 74065 - 16.381/382)
- Paderewski, Ignacy Jan Collection, 126 prints, 6 postcards / 1 album, 2 envelopes (Box 75017 - Photo file)
  - One album containing 83 prints and 4 postcards depicting Paderewski at various events and others, including Mr. and Mrs. Bagniewski, Jan Ciechanowski, King George VI, Mr. and Mrs. Gutowski, Monsignor Kaczynski, I. Kollupajlo-la Grange, Tommy Majewski, Stanislaw Mikolajczk, Lily Pons, Wladyslaw Raczkiewicz, Eleanor Roosevelt, Wladyslaw Sikorski, Minister Stanoczyk, Mrs. Edward I. Stotesbury, Aniela Strakacz, Sylwin Strakcz, Tadeusz Styka, Francis X. Swietlik, A. Syski, Antonina Wilkonska, Mr. and Mrs. Witkowski, and Adam Zamoyski, 1923-1941, and scenes from his funeral at Arlington Cemetery, July 6, 1941 (Folder fA)
    Includes prints depicting busts of Paderewski by Malvina Hoffman and Tregor.
  - 1 print depicting a portrait of Paderewski by Tadeusz Styka, 1939; 1 print depicting Paderewski with Wladyslaw Sikorski, 1941; 2 postcards and 1 print depicting lodgings of Polish soldiers interned in Switzerland during World War II, with Paderewski's portrait hung on the walls; and 2 miscellany prints (Box B)
  - 30 prints depicting atrocities committed in Poland during World War II; 6 prints depicting Polish children being fed by the Commission for Polish Relief, Winter 1940-41; 2 prints depicting Polish soldiers, including one being decorated by General Sikorski with the Virtuti Military order (Folder C)
- Papen (Franz Von) Collection, undated; 5 prints / 2 envelopes (Box 49002 - 10 A-V)
  - 3 photos of Franz von Papen, his family and his Saar Valley home, undated (Folder A)
  - 2 photos of Crown prince Wilhelm, Crown princess Cecilie, and Princess Alexandrine of Germany, undated (Folder mB)
- Park, Alice Collection, undated; 18 photographs / 79 postcards / 2 envelopes (Box 30017 - 10.A-V)
  - 1 print of Hannah Sheehy-Skeffinton; 1 print of Warren K. Billings; 2 prints of Rosika Schwimmer; 1 print of Rosika Schwimmer with Louis Calhern, Dorothy Gish, and Edgar Barrier; 1 print of Elizabeth Cady Stanton; 1 print of Florence Holbrook and Lola Maverick Lloyd; 1 print of Heart Mountain, Wyoming, Japanese Internment Camp; 4 prints of child laborers; 3 prints of John E. Jones; 3 miscellaneous prints, undated (Folder A)
  - 74 peace postcards; 5 Industrial Worker of the World postcards, undated (Box B)
  - 1 illustrated chart of the members of the U.S. Congress who voted against American entry into World War I, undated (Folder mC)
- Parmelee, Ruth A. Collection, undated; 4 prints / 1 oversize envelope (Box 74099 - Oversize photo file Envelope mA)
  3 prints of Erzurum and 1 of Trebizond, Turkey.
- Pasternak Family Collection, undated; 21 prints, 1 postcard, 2 glass plates / 12 envelopes (Box 38) (Box 96063 - 34.05/06)
- Pastuhov, Vladimir D. Collection, 1 oversize envelope / 13 albums (Box 67023 - 10.A-V)
  - 4 oversize prints relating to China, undated (Folder mA)
  - 2 albums relating to the League of Nations Harbin Relief Commission of Russian Emigrants in Northern China, 1931; 1 album relating to anti-Japanese sentiment in China, 1929-1932; 1 album relating to terrorist activity in Northern Manchuria (Folder fB)
  - 3 duplicate albums relating to terrorist activity in Northern Manchuria; 2 albums relating to the Southern Manchurian Railroad Company, undated (Folder fC)
  - 2 duplicates of album relating to the activity of the Harbin Committee; 1 related album relating to the same committee; 1 album relating to anti-Japanese sentiment in China, undated (Folder fD)
- Pathfinder Press Collection, undated; 8 prints / 1 envelope (Box 92116 - 10.A-V Envelope A)
  8 prints of the Mexican-American communist Charles Shipman.
- Pats, Konstantin Collection, 1991; 2 prints / 1 envelope (Box 77075 - Photo file Envelope A)
  2 prints depicting the graves of Konstantin and Helma Pats in Tallinn.
- Pauker, Guy J. Collection, 145 prints / 5 envelopes / 278 slides (Box 82096 - 10.A-V, film shelf, slide cabinet)
  - 145 prints depicting scenes, events and people in Indonesia, Thailand and other Southeast Asian countries, circa 1950-1970 (Folder A-D)
  - 278 slides. Same as A-D, undated (Folder slide cabinet)
  - 1 (16mm) film of interview with A. Sukarno and D. Aidit, January 1959 (Folder film shelf)
- Pauley Mission to Manchuria Collection, undated; 1 album (Box fXX002 - 10.A-V)
  Photographs documenting findings of the U.S. Mission to Manchuria headed by Ambassador Edwin W. Pauley regarding the extent of destruction of industry in Manchuria and the quantity of industrial equipment removed by Soviet occupying forces.
- Peck, Willys R. Collection, Jul 8, 1946; 1 print / 1 envelope (Box 53005 - 10.A-V)
  1 print of T.K. Chang, William L. Montgomery, Willys R. Peck in San Francisco, California.
- Persico, Joseph E. Collection, 1942-1978; 66 prints, 48 negatives / 1 envelope (Box 81137 - 10.A-V Envelope A)
  Depicts U.S. Office of Strategic Services agents and veterans, and scenes related to American secret service operations in Germany during World War II. Includes photographs published in the book by J.E. Persico, "Piercing the Reich" (1979).
- Petain, Henri (Marshal of France) Collection, undated; 5 photos / plus 5 dups. / 1 envelope (Box XX092 - 10.A-V Envelope m)
  5 photos and dups. depicting Petain as General.
- Peterkin (Wilbur J.) Collection, 403 photographs / 2 envelopes, 1 album (Box 76018 - 10.A-V)
  - 92 photographs depicting W. J. Peterkin's activities as executive and commanding officer of the U.S. Observer Mission to the Chinese Communists, 1944-45 (Folder A)
    Includes prints of Communist Chinese leaders and views of Yenan.
  - 1 photo album of 245 prints of China, Nigeria, and India at the time of World War II, undated (Folder fB)
  - 66 prints depicting the International Peace Hospital with the Chinese communist forces, 1944 (Folder C)
- Petrenko (Glenn) Collection, 1964-65; 70 prints / 1 envelope (Box 76078 - 10.A-V)
  Collection of 70 photos concerning Vietnam collected by Col. Glenn Petrenko while serving in Vietnam as U.S. Military Adviser. Included are pictures of Gen. W.C. Westmoreland, U.S.A, and of former congressman C.E. Gallagher of New Jersey.
- Phillips (James H.) Collection, 9 prints / 3 negatives / 1 envelope (Box XX159 - 10.AV)
  9 prints and 3 negatives depicting scenes from the military career of Major General Phillips, including photos of Gen. Eisenhower, Maj. Gen. Parks, Maj. Gen. Mitchell, and Major General Fritz Bayerlien of the German Army. 2 photos depicting Phillips as a lieutenant, 1924, 1925. 7 prints and 3 negatives circa 1943-45.
- Phillips, Loring Collection, 1918-1919; 12 prints / 1 envelope (Box 82011 - 10.A-V Envelope A)
  Depicts American and Allied military leaders and activities in France during World War I.
- Philip (William R.) Collection, 379 photos / 7 envelopes (Box 68007 - 10 A-V)
  - 289 prints of military aerial photographs of the Normandy Coast prior to the invasion of June 6, 1944 (Folder A-D)
  - 2 negatives from the album depicting Joachim von Ribbentrop's trip to Moscow depicting von Ribbentrop, Joseph Stalin, and Vyacheslav Molotov signing the Russian-German pact, 1939 (Box E)
  - 6 photos of Adolf Hitler, Eva Braun, and others at Hitler's mountain retreat, undated (Box F)
  - 82 photos of leading NAZI officials, undated (Box G)
- Pickett (Carrie) Collection, undated; 1 envelope / 18 prints (Box 73083 - 10 A-V)
  18 photos of Carrie Pickett and scenes in Poland and Siberia depicting relief work of the American Red Cross.
- Pictorial Miscellany Collection, 14 envelopes, 1 box (Box XX773 - 10.A-V)
- Pirnie, Malcolm Collection, undated; 6 prints / 1 envelope / 1 oversize box (Box 58007 - 10.A-V, 58007 - 8M.02)
  - 4 prints of American Red Cross activities in Russia; 2 prints of the ship "Empress of Asia:, 1917 (Folder A)
  - 1 photograph album of the American Red Cross Mission to Russia, 1917 (Folder fB)
- Platt (Frances Carson) Collection, undated; 2 envelopes / 117 photographs (Box XX208 - 10.A-V)
  - 12 prints and 101 photographic reproductions of drawings depicting A.E.F. activities in France in World War I, including scenes of trench life and war damage, 1918 (Folder A)
  - 4 prints of Charles G. Dawes as a brigadier general, U.S. Army, 1918 (Box B)
- Platt, Philip S. Collection, 1916; 3 prints / 1 envelope (Box 57022 - 10.A-V)
  Photographs of members of the Commission for Relief in Belgium playing baseball in Brussels.
- Poland, William B. Collection, 1922; 1 album (Box XX503 - 8.24 Envelope B)
  Album of photographs depicting relief work of the American Relief Administration (ARA) in Poland, presented by the Polsko-Amerykanski Komitet Pomocy Dzieciom to William B. Poland in gratitude for his relief activities with the ARA in Poland.
- Poland. Ministerstwo Informacji I Dokumentacjii Collection, 1939-1945; 500 prints / 8 envelopes (Box 59008 - 10.A-V)
- Poland, Ministerstwo Spraw Zagranicznych Collection, 1940-1943; 162 prints / 13 envelopes (Box 59003 - Photo file)
- Polish Information Center (New York, N.Y.) records, 1940-1945; 23 prints / 2 envelopes (Box 48018 - 10.A-V)
- Poland. Polskie Siy Zbrojne. Collection, 1312 prints / 22 envelopes (Box 46036 - 10.A-V)
  - 139 prints depicting Polish military operations and personnel during World War II, undated (Folder A-D)
  - 11 prints depicting the Polish Army in the USSR, undated (Box E)
  - 15 prints depicting women in the Polish armed forces, undated (Box F)
  - 34 prints depicting Polish military personnel and civilians in Africa and other foreign countries at the end of World War II, undated (Box G)
  - 693 prints depicting Polish military personnel and military operations during World War II, undated (Folder H-P)
  - 50 prints depicting scenes in Warsaw during World War II, undated (Folder Q)
  - 46 prints depicting the Polish underground movement during World War II and the Warsaw Uprising, August-October, 1944 (Folder R)
  - 50 prints depicting Captain Gutowski and his squadron in England, undated (Folder S)
  - 7 prints depicting Poles in concentration camps and displaced persons, undated (Folder T)
  - 46 prints depicting Polish statesmen, military officers, and dignitaries, undated (Folder U)
  - 91 prints depicting daily scenes in Poland, Polish citizens and various places of interest in Poland, circa World War II, undated (Folder V)
- Polish National Committee of America Collection, undated; 59 postcards / 1 envelope (Box XX253 - 10.A-V)
  59 postcards depicting scenes of destruction in Poland during W.W.I, coins of Lithuania-Poland, Polish army from the U.S. in France, W.W.I.
- Popovic, Zarko Collection, undated (Box 75108 - 10.A.V.)
  3 photographs of Royal Yugoslav armed forces in exile during World War II, in training with the British in Egypt.
- Popper, Karl R. Papers, 146 prints / 28 envelopes (Box 86039 - 10.A-V)
  See the Sir Karl R. Popper Papers register for list of photographs. See also the register to the additional Sir Karl Raimund Popper Incremental Material for more documentation.
- Posters Collection, circa 1900-2002 (Box XX343 - 10.A-V)
  See register for more information on photographic duplications of the Posters Collection.
- Pototskii, S.N. Collection, 3 prints / 1 envelope (Box m47015 - 10 A-V)
  Two photographs of the USSR trade delegation to Denmark, circa 1924. One photograph of graves of Russian soldiers in northern Schleswig, Denmark, circa 1931.
- Powers, Joshua B. Collection, 145 photos / 7 duplicates / 24 negatives / 1 album and 5 envelopes (Box 68026 - 10.A-V)
- Procopiu, Irina Collection, undated; 224 prints / 1 envelope / 1 album (Box 79002 - 10.A-V, 79002 - 8M.02)
  - 37 prints depicting King Ferdinand and Queen Marie of Romania and their children before and after World War I; various royal ceremonies and events, including a print of King Ferdinand I Foundation in Jassy, capital of Moldavia, Romania, undated (Folder A)
  - Photo album of 187 prints relating to the American Red Cross Commission in Romania during and after World War I, including prints of the royal family of Romania and of Romanian peasants and refugees, undated (Box B)
- Pullen, Harold F. Collection, 1918-1920; 44 prints / 1 envelope (Box 80044 - 10.A-V)
  Photographs of scenes at the U.S. Naval Academy, and of U.S. Naval vessels and installations.
- Putnam, John F. Collection, 1945-1946; 241 slides / 12 boxes in 3 envelopes (Box 79087 - 10.A-V)
  Depicts scenes in Japan. See Preliminary Inventory for a description of photographs in this collection
- Putnam (Ruth) Collection, 85 postcards / 119 photos / 3 envelopes (Box XX132 - 8.13)
  - 85 postcards depicting various scenes, individuals, and places in Luxemburg, 1918-19 (Folder A)
  - 119 photos depicting various scenes, individuals, places, U.S. and other military forces in Luxemburg, 1918-19 (Folder B-C)
- Quinn (Frederick) Collection, 38 prints and 1 postcard / 1 envelope (Box 72099 - 10.A-V)